80000hours.org 2019-12-24

# Privacy policy - 80,000 Hours

Effective date: January 16, 2019

80,000 Hours is part of the Centre for Effective Altruism (“us”, “we”, or “our”), a registered charity in England and Wales (Charity Number 1149828) and a registered 501(c)(3) Exempt Organization in the USA (EIN 47-1988398). Within the Centre for Effective Altruism, the 80,000 Hours team operates the 80000hours.org website and related programmes.

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.

## Definitions

  * **Service**  
Service is the 80000hours.org website, related programmes operated by the 80,000 Hours team, and all other programmes operated by the Centre for Effective Altruism
  * **Personal Data**  
Personal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from those data (or from those and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).
  * **Usage Data**  
Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).
  * **Cookies**  
Cookies are small pieces of data stored on your device (computer or mobile device).
  * **Data Controller**  
Data Controller means the natural or legal person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal information are, or are to be, processed.  
For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your Personal Data.
  * **Data Processors (or Service Providers)**  
Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any natural or legal person who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.  
We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.
  * **Data Subject (or User)**  
Data Subject is any living individual who is using our Service and is the subject of Personal Data.

## Information Collection and Use

We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.

### Types of Data Collected

#### Personal Data

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Data”). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

  * First name and last name
  * Email address
  * Cookies and Usage Data
  * Information regarding your career plans, professional experience and qualifications
  * Information regarding your interests and goals, for example which problems you’d like to use your career to solve or where you’d like to work.
  * Demographic information such as country of residence, university affiliation, age, preferences and interests
  * Other information relevant to user research

We may use your Personal Data to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send, or by contacting us.

##### Special Category Data (also known as Sensitive Personal Information)

Unless you specifically provide it to us while applying for or using our Service, we do not collect special category data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data, or information about criminal convictions and offences). In cases where you may decide to provide special category data (for example when applying for assistance from our in-person team) we collect this data under the legal basis of consent and you will be prompted to give consent for the processing of such data for the relevant purpose.

#### Usage Data

We may also collect information how the Service is accessed and used (“Usage Data”). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

#### Tracking & Cookies Data

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information.

Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.

Examples of Cookies we use:

  *  **Session Cookies.** We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.
  *  **Preference Cookies.** We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.
  *  **Security Cookies.** We use Security Cookies for security purposes.

## Use of Data

We use the data collected for various purposes:

  * To provide and maintain our Service
  * To notify you about changes to our Service
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so
  * To provide user support
  * To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Service
  * To monitor the usage of our Service
  * To detect, prevent and address technical issues
  * To assess the social impact of our programmes
  * To support decisions regarding who should be offered certain aspects of our Service (for example assistance from our in-person team)
  * To provide you with news, special offers and general information about other goods, services and events we think you may be interested in

As a general rule the Personal Data we collect will remain confidential within, and only accessible to, the 80,000 Hours team. We may, however, share the Personal Data we collect with our parent organisation – the Centre for Effective Altruism – in line with the purposes described above. In addition, we may share Personal Data with other third parties where it is necessary for the provision of our Coaching and Recruiting services.

### Coaching

By applying for and using our Coaching Service, you accept the practices described in this general policy and those described in our coaching terms & privacy policy.

### Recruiting

By using our Recruiting Service, you accept the practices described in this policy and those described in our recruiting terms & privacy policy.

## Legal Basis for Processing Personal Data Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

If you are from the European Economic Area (EEA), the legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy depends on the Personal Data we collect and the specific context in which we collect it.

The Centre for Effective Altruism may process your Personal Data because:

  * We need to perform a contract with you
  * You have given us permission to do so
  * The processing is in our legitimate interests and it’s not overridden by your rights
  * We need to comply with the law

Where we rely on legitimate interests as the legal basis for processing your Personal Data, these interests are:

  * To keep our records updated and to study how our Service is used
  * To administer and protect the charity and web presence (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting)
  * To inform our marketing strategies
  * To assess your suitability for potential roles or opportunities at organizations that 80,000 Hours is assisting, and to contact you about such roles
  * To best serve our charitable aims in the most efficient manner possible

## Retention of Data

The Centre for Effective Altruism will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

The Centre for Effective Altruism will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Service, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods.

## Transfer of Data

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to United States and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

The Centre for Effective Altruism will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

If any websites now owned by the Centre for Effective Altruism transfer ownership, for example because they spin off to become a separate project or are acquired by another nonprofit, your information may be transferred to the new owner.

## Disclosure of Data

### Disclosure for Law Enforcement

Under certain circumstances, The Centre for Effective Altruism may be required to disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency).

### Legal Requirements

The Centre for Effective Altruism may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

  * To comply with a legal obligation
  * To protect and defend the rights or property of The Centre for Effective Altruism
  * To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
  * To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
  * To protect against legal liability

## Security of Data

The security of your Personal Data is important to us. To prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place reasonable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the data we collect. It is important to remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure, and therefore we cannot 100% guarantee the security of the Personal Data we collect.

## “Do Not Track” Signals

We do not support Do Not Track (“DNT”). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.

You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.

## Your Data Protection Rights Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. The Centre for Effective Altruism aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data.

If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.

In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:

  * **The right to access, update or to delete the information we have on you.** Whenever made possible, you can access, update or request deletion of your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to perform these actions yourself, please contact us to assist you.
  * **The right of rectification.** You have the right to have your information rectified if that information is inaccurate or incomplete.
  * **The right to object.** You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Data.
  * **The right of restriction.** You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information.
  * **The right to data portability.** You have the right to be provided with a copy of the information we have on you in a structured, machine-readable and commonly used format.
  * **The right to withdraw consent.** You also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where The Centre for Effective Altruism relied on your consent to process your personal information.

Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

You have the right to complain to a Data Protection Authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority in the European Economic Area (EEA).

## Service Providers

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service (“Service Providers”), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

### Analytics

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service. Such third parties include, but are not limited to:

  * **Google Analytics**  
Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  
You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

  * **Mixpanel**  
Mixpanel is provided by Mixpanel Inc  
You can prevent Mixpanel from using your information for analytics purposes by opting-out. To opt-out of Mixpanel service, please visit this page: <https://mixpanel.com/optout/>  
For more information on what type of information Mixpanel collects, please visit the Terms of Use page of Mixpanel: <https://mixpanel.com/terms/>

### Behavioral Remarketing

The Centre for Effective Altruism uses remarketing services to advertise on third party websites to you after you visited our Service. We and our third-party vendors use cookies to inform, optimize and serve ads based on your past visits to our Service.

The behavioral remarketing services we use include, but are not limited to:

  * **Google AdWords**  
Google AdWords remarketing service is provided by Google Inc.  
You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize the Google Display Network ads by visiting the Google Ads Settings page: <http://www.google.com/settings/ads>  
Google also recommends installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on – <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> – for your web browser. Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on provides visitors with the ability to prevent their data from being collected and used by Google Analytics.  
For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>
  * **Twitter**  
Twitter remarketing service is provided by Twitter Inc.  
You can opt-out from Twitter’s interest-based ads by following their instructions: <https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405>  
You can learn more about the privacy practices and policies of Twitter by visiting their Privacy Policy page: <https://twitter.com/privacy>
  * **Facebook**  
Facebook remarketing service is provided by Facebook Inc.  
You can learn more about interest-based advertising from Facebook by visiting this page: <https://www.facebook.com/help/164968693837950>  
To opt-out from Facebook’s interest-based ads follow these instructions from Facebook: <https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217>

Facebook adheres to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising established by the Digital Advertising Alliance. You can also opt-out from Facebook and other participating companies through the Digital Advertising Alliance in the USA <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>, the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada in Canada <http://youradchoices.ca/> or the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance in Europe <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>, or opt-out using your mobile device settings.  
For more information on the privacy practices of Facebook, please visit Facebook’s Data Policy: <https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation>

### Marketing automation

We use MailChimp as our marketing automation platform. When you join our newsletter, or give us your email address for other reasons, the information you provide may be transferred to MailChimp for processing in accordance with their [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and [Terms](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/).

## Links to Other Sites

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

## Children’s Privacy

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 (“Children”).

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

## Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page and updating the “effective date” at the top of this page.

If you are an active or previously active user of our Service, we may also notify you of substantive changes to this Privacy Policy via email and/or a prominent notice on our Service, prior to the change becoming effective.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

If you would like to exercise your rights under EU GDPR or have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us:

  * By email: privacy@80000hours.org
  * By mail: Centre for Effective Altruism USA, 2054 University Ave Suite 300 Berkeley, CA 94704 United States
